MUHAMMAD **FAHAD**

University of Punjab, Lahore ↑
03002674000 ↓
fahad.naturalist@gmail.com ■



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An involved Biology teacher with experience of over 5 years in teaching Biology to intermediate & high school students. I always plan lessons according to the needs of the students involving real-life examples to maximize their learning. I believe in hard work and life-long learning. I believe to add value to the organization I work with as well as to the learning of the students.



EDUCATION

BSc (Hons.) Entomology (Zoology) | University of Punjab, Lahore 2014 – 2018 (CGPA, 3.61)

Internship: National Center of Excellence in Molecular Biology, Lahore



EXPERIENCE

Unique Science Academy | DHA, Phase-5 Lahore

FEBRUARY 2018 - PRESENT

- Teaching Biology to the secondary school students (BISE Lahore and Federal board)
- Conduct monthly tests, guizzes and discussions
- Administer student counselling

The Guardian Academy | Johar Town, Lahore

DECEMBER 2014 - OCTOBER 2017

- Taught Science and Biology to junior and senior classes
- Conducted weekly tests and administered results and discussions
- Administered Parent Teacher Meetings

Home Tutor | Lahore

2014 - PRESENT

- Currently teaching two students of class 8 (DHA Education System)
- Taught students of matric pre-medical (Session 2014-2015)
- Taught Intermediate pre-medical students (Session 2015-2017)
- Taught two students of LACAS school primary class (2015-2018)

X

SKILLS

- Communication skills
- Classroom management

- Student counselling
- Graduate Record Exam (GRE), 295